在所有搭载Android系统的设备中
Of all the Android launch devices,
Nexus 1在我心中一直都占有着一个特殊的位置
the Nexus 1 will always hold a special place in my heart.
这并不是说我的第一款Android设备  HTC G1就不重要了
That's not to take anything away from my first Android device,
HTC G1以其独特的下巴部分和侧滑全键盘
the HTC G1, that launched Android to the world with its distinctive chin
把Android系统推向世界
and slide-out keyboard.
还有HTC Magic  我加入Google后
Or the HTC Magic, first prerelease android phone
内部试用的第一款预发布Android手机
I got to dog food when I joined Google.
HTC Magic也是第一款被赠送给
And the first, the wave of devices we gave every attendee
09年Google I/O大会每位与会者的手机
starting at Google I/O in 2009.
2010年Android从仅仅是有趣变成了全球化的现象
2010 was the year Android went from "that's interesting" to global phenomenon.
5月份Android系统每天的激活量有10万
Growing from 100,000 activations a day in May,
到了12月份这个数字就增长到超过30万了
to over 300,000 by December.
这个增长大大得益于摩托罗拉Droid的发布
That was seriously helped by the release of the Motorola Droid.
我到现在都记得  随着每台Droid的重启
I can still remember the offices here in Building 44,
这里的44号楼办公室中不停地回响着Droid的经典铃音
echoing with the constant refrain of "Droid" as each device rebooted.
Droid是第一款外观更纤薄  分辨率更高  续航更持久的Android设备
The Droid was the first of the thinner, higher res, more powerful Android devices
自问世就成为了Android设备的标准
that have since become standard.
也正是Droid在美国通过Verizon的上市
And it was also the device whose release on Verizon here in the U.S.,
真正地开创了Android系统激活的大潮
really kicked off the flood of Android activations.
但那时我还在伦敦  Droid又仅支持CDMA制式
But I was a Londoner then, and the Droid was a [inaudible] only phone,
所以我并没有真正地使用Droid
so it was never really a device I truly used.
后来  就出了Nexus 1  代号为Passion
Then, there was the Nexus 1, code-named Passion.
这是第一款让我领略到纯净Android系统的手机  也是我们带着参加2010年的
The first device I felt was pure Android, was also the phone we brought with us
Android开发者实验室世界巡回之旅的手机
on our 2010 Android Developer Labs World Tour.
我和我的同事们横穿全球
Me and my colleagues traveled across the world.
10天之内走了7个城市  通过演示活动和免费赠送一部Nexus 1
Seven cities in ten days, introducing over 20,000 developers
我们向2万多开发者介绍了Android系统
to Android by way of presentations and a free Nexus 1.
结果是我在欧洲交了不少朋友
As a result, I made a lot of friends across Europe,
并知道了在穿越斯德哥尔摩的雪堆和
and learned exactly how many boxes of phones
柏林结冰的马路时  自己到底能背多少箱手机
I can carry across snow drifts in Stockholm, and icy roads in Berlin.
自那以后  Nexus S 4和5这三款手机都持续改进
Since then, The Nexus S4 and 5 have each improved on what it takes
并成为了出色的Android手机
to make a great Android phone.
全球的原始设备制造商还生产了数以千计的各种各样的Android设备
And OEMs across the world, have created thousands of different Android devices.
从Motorola Xoom开始
Starting with the Motorola Xoom,
Android正式进军平板市场
which led Android's official expansion into tablets,
也为Nexus 7和10带了路
and leading the way for the Nexus 7 and 10.
但那仅仅是一个开始
But that was just the start.
这些改变为Android大规模占领市场铺平了道路
Those changes paved the way for the Android [inaudible]
使Android系统成为所有设备的后台大脑
to grow into what could be, the brains behind anything
从电话和平板  到电视  汽车和可穿戴设备  比如Android Wear
from phones and tablets, to TVs, cars and wearables, like Android Wear.
谁也无法知道Android下一个作品是什么
It's impossible to know, what comes next.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
也许下个Android设备就是Android机器人本身
Maybe the next Android devices, will be Androids themselves.